A Guide to the Department of Education, School Buildings Service, Architectural drawings and plans, 1920-1970
Library of Virginia
- Series III. Standard Plans. (Box 10-13., Reel 1837.)
  - Standard Plans - Railing Details, n.d. (Folder 10, Folder 13-L-11)
  - Standard Plans - Window Details, n.d. (Folder 10, Folder 13-L-11)
  - Standard Plans - Book Shelving, n.d. (Folder 10, Folder 13-L-11)
  - Standard Plans - Miscellaneous Home Economics Cottages- 10, Feb 1934 (Folder 10, Folder 13-R-1)
  - Standard Plans - Standard Home Economics Cottages- 1-B, Jan 1940 (Folder 10, Folder 13-L-12)
  - Standard Plans - Miscellaneous Home Economics Cottages- 11, Dec 1935 (Folder 10, Folder 13-R-1)
  - Standard Plans - Miscellaneous Home Economics Cottages- 11-A, Jan 1937 (Folder 10, Folder 13-R-1)
  - Standard Plans - Miscellaneous Home Economics Cottages- 12, Nov 1935 (Folder 10, Folder 13-R-1)
  - Standard Plans - Miscellaneous Home Economics Cottages- 14, July 1936 (Folder 10, Folder 13-R-1)
  - Standard Plans - Miscellaneous Home Economics Cottages- 14-C, May 1937 (Folder 10, Folder 13-R-1)
  - Standard Plans - Miscellaneous Home Economics Cottages- 15, Aug 193- (Folder 10, Folder 13-R-1)
  - Standard Plans - Miscellaneous Home Economics Cottages- 15-B, Feb 193- (Folder 10, Folder 13-R-1)
  - Standard Plans - Miscellaneous Home Economics Cottages- 16 (Folder 10, Folder 13-R-1)
  - Standard Plans - Home Economics & Agricultural Building- 684, May 1935 (Folder 10, Folder 13-R-2)
  - Standard Plans - Home Economics & Agricultural Shop Building- 684-B (Used at Draper-Pulaski Co.), Aug 1937 (Folder 10, Folder 13-R-2)
  - Standard Plans - Home Economics & Agricultural Shop Building- 774, 774-B, July 1938 (Folder 10, Folder 13-R-2)
  - Standard Plans - Two Room Prefabricated Building (Steelcraft Manufacturing Co.), n.d. (Folder 10, Folder 13-L-10)
  - Standard Plans - Standard Four Room, May 1925 (Folder 10, Folder 13-L-4)
  - Standard Plans - Home Economics & Agricultural Shop Building- (Used For Midway & Sunnyside-Dinwiddie Co.), Aug 1937 (Folder 10, Folder 13-R-2)
  - Standard Plans - Standard Two Room Brick Veneer, Aug 1937 (Folder 10, Folder 13-L-2)
  - Standard Plans - Standard Four Room, May 1928 (Folder 10, Folder 13-L-4)
  - Standard Plans - Standard Emergency & Temporary Buildings, 1930-1937 (Folder 10, Folder 13-L-9)
  - Standard Plans - Standard One Room, Sept 1927 (Folder 10, Folder 13-L-1)
  - Standard Plans - Standard Two Room Frame, Sept 1927 (Folder 10, Folder 13-L-2)
  - Standard Plans - Standard Two Room, July 1928 (Folder 10, Folder 13-L-2)
  - Standard Plans - Special Two Room, July 1935 (Folder 10, Folder 13-L-2)
  - Standard Plans - Standard Two Room Frame, Oct 1937 (Folder 10, Folder 13-L-2)
  - Standard Plans - Standard Two Room- Addition, July 1940 (Folder 10, Folder 13-L-2)
  - Standard Plans - Standard Two Room, Feb 1942 (Folder 10, Folder 13-L-2)
  - Standard Plans - Standard (Miscellaneous), n.d. (Folder 10, Folder 13-L-2)
  - Standard Plans - Three Room Special, Jan 1935 (Folder 10, Folder 13-L-3)
  - Standard Plans - Three Room, Dec 1945 (Folder 10, Folder 13-L-3)
  - Standard Plans - Gymnasium, April 1938 (Folder 10, Folder 13-L-8)
  - Standard Plans - Standard Two Room, Sept 1935 (Folder 10, Folder 13-L-2)
  - Standard Plans - Four Room Special, July 1923 (Folder 10, Folder 13-L-4)
  - Standard Plans - Standard- Eight Room, n.d. (Folder 10, Folder 13-L-7)
  - Standard Plans - Standard One Story - Six Room, 1925 (Folder 10, Folder 13-L-6)
  - Standard Plans - Four Room School & Auditorium, Oct 1924 (Folder 10, Folder 13-L-5)
  - Standard Plans - Standard Frame - Auditorium & Gymnasium, July 1938 (Folder 10, Folder 13-L-8)
  - Standard Plans - Standard Four Room Frame, May 193- (Folder 10, Folder 13-L-4)
  - Standard Plans - Standard Four Room Brick, Sept 1933 (Folder 10, Folder 13-L-4)
  - Standard Plans - Four Room (Reworked), May 1930 (Folder 10, Folder 13-L-4)
  - Standard Plans - Four Room, n.d. (Folder 10, Folder 13-L-4)
  - Standard Plans - Standard Four Room, Jan 1927 (Folder 10, Folder 13-L-4)
  - Standard Plans - Standard One Story - Eight Room, Feb 1924 (Folder 10, Folder 13-L-7)
  - Standard Plans - Community Canning Facility, 1943-1944 (Folder 11, Folder 15-8)
  - Standard Plans - Parking Facilities- Cars and Buses, Science Classes Facilities, n.d., 1962 (Folder 11, Folder 15-5)
  - Standard Plans - Cosmetology and Practical Nursing Facilities, n.d. (Folder 11, Folder 15-7)
  - Standard Plans - Administrative Units, Art Facilities, Distributive Facilities, Health and Physical Education Facilities, Health Services Facilities: Reduced Floor Plans, n.d. (Folder 11, Folder 15)
  - Standard Plans - Business Education Facilities, n.d. (Folder 11, Folder 15-6)
  - Standard Plans - Health, Physical Education, and Recreation Facilities, n.d. (Folder 11, Folder 15-3)
  - Standard Plans - Three, Four and Six Bay Standard School Bus With Lift, 1960-1962 (Folder 11, Folder 15-1)
  - Standard Plans - Standard Plans for Vocational School Buildings, 1940-1963 (Folder 11, Folder 15-2)
  - Standard Plans - Home Economics Facilities [and classroom designs], 1950-1967, n.d. (Folder 11, Folder 15-4)
  - Miscellaneous - [Diazo prints of agriculture, vocational, and cosmetology facilities], Various (Folder 12, Folder 17-7)
  - Miscellaneous - [Tracings, plans, and charts for 1954 School Planning Manual], 1954 (Folder 12, Folder 17-6)
  - Miscellaneous - Log Cabin School/ Buchanan County, Virginia/ Department School Buildings/ State Department of Education / Richmond, VA, 1933 (Folder 12, Folder 17-5)
  - Standard Plans - Standard 6 Room School Building/ Prepared State Board of Education Richmond VA, n.d. (Folder 12, Folder 17-3)
  - Standard Plans - Vocational Agriculture Building / Plan B, 1950 (Folder 12, Folder 16-4)
  - Standard Plans - Vocational Agriculture Building / Plan B-B, 1950 (Folder 12, Folder 16-6)
  - Standard Plans - Vocational Agriculture Building & Facility for Landscape Horticulture, 1965 (Folder 12, Folder 16-7)
  - Standard Plans - Vocational Agriculture Building / Plan A, Vocational Agriculture Building / Plan B-B-2, 1951 (Folder 12, Folder 16-8)
  - Standard Plans - Standard Plans Two Room Elementary School for the State Board of Education / Commonwealth of Virginia / Fleming R. Hurt & Charlie D. Hurt, Jr. / Architects / 526 West Main St. Waynesboro, Virginia, 1952 (Folder 12, Folder 17-2)
  - Standard Plans - Vocational Agriculture Building / Plan A, 1950 (Folder 12, Folder 16-3)
  - Standard Plans - Standard Plan for a 4 Room School, 1951 (Folder 12, Folder 17-4)
  - Standard Plans - Four-Room Room Elementary School for the State Board of Education/ Commonwealth of Virginia / Fleming R. Hurt & Charlie D. Hurt, Jr. Architects / 526 West Main St. Waynesboro, Virginia, 1951 (Folder 12, Folder 17-1)
  - Standard Plans - Standard Agricultural Building, 1935 (Folder 12, Folder 16-2)
  - Standard Plans - Vocational Agriculture Building, 1951 (Folder 12, Folder 16-1)
  - Standard Plans - Vocational Agriculture Building / Plan B-B, 1950 (Folder 12, Folder 16-5)
  - Standard Plans - Woodworking Bench, 1941 (Folder 12, Folder 16-2)
  - Standard Plans - Two Laboratory Agriculture Building, 1931 (Folder 12, Folder 16-2)
  - Standard Plans - Standard Agricultural Building, 1928 (Folder 12, Folder 16-2)
  - Standard Plans - Standard Agricultural Building, 1925 (Folder 12, Folder 16-2)
  - Standard Plans - Standard Agricultural Shop Plan No. 985, 1939 (Folder 12, Folder 16-2)
  - Standard Plans - Standard Agricultural Shop, 1939 (Folder 12, Folder 16-2)
  - Standard Plans - Standard Vocational Shop, 1940 (Folder 12, Folder 16-2)
  - Standard Plans - Suggested Vocational Building for Radford Va. and Pulaski Va., n.d. (Folder 12, Folder 16-2)
  - Standard Plans - Supply Cabinet for Agricultural Shops, 1942 (Folder 12, Folder 16-2)
  - Miscellaneous - [Department of Education - Organizational Charts], 1949-1966 (Folder 13, Folder 19-1)
  - Standard Plans - Seven Class Room Elementary School for the State Board of Education - Commonwealth of Virginia/ J. Henley Walker, Jr. Architect / Richmond, Virginia, 1952 (Folder 13, Folder 18-1)
  - Standard Plans - Three Room Addition to Seven Class Room Elementary School for the State Board of Education - Commonwealth of Virginia/ J. Henley Walker, Jr. Architect/ Richmond, Virginia, 1952 (Folder 13, Folder 18-2)
  - Standard Plans - Auditorium Addition to Seven Class Room Elementary School for the State Board of Education - Commonwealth of Virginia/ J. Henley Walker, Jr. Architect/ Richmond, Virginia, 1952 (Folder 13, Folder 18-3)
  - Standard Plans - [Elevations and plans for elementary school classrooms], n.d. (Folder 13, Folder 18-4)
- Series IV. Drawings on Microfilm Only. (Reel 1830-1832.)
  Contains a variety of school drawings and plans for which the Library of Virginia does not hold the originals. This material is available only on microfilm.
  - East Fauquier Elementary (Now P.B. Smith Elementary), drawing 30-72A (Reel 1830)
  - C.M. Bradley Elementary, drawing 30-73A (Reel 1830)
  - Gainsboro Elementary, drawing 34-38D (Reel 1830)
  - Senseny Road Elementary, drawing 34-47B (Reel 1830)
  - Dowell J. Howard Vocational, drawing 34-49A (Reel 1830)
  - Abingdon District Elementary, drawing 36-25A (Reel 1830)
  - Beaverdam Elementary, drawing 42-2E (Reel 1830)
  - Highland Springs H.S., drawing 43-19E (Reel 1830)
  - Gym, Douglas Freeman H.S., drawing 43-41D (Reel 1830)
  - Fair Oaks Elementary, drawing 43-20B (Reel 1830)
  - Laburnam Elementary, drawing 43-43C (Reel 1830)
  - Addition to Varina H.S., drawing 43-58D (Reel 1830)
  - Gym addition to Varina H.S., drawing 43-58D (Reel 1830)
  - Gym addition to J.R. Tucker H.S., drawing 43-60D (Reel 1830)
  - Gym addition to Henrico H.S., drawing 43-61B (Reel 1830)
  - King and Queen Elementary, drawing 49-20E (Reel 1830)
  - Central H.S., drawing 49-28C (Reel 1830)
  - Jasper Elementary, drawing 52-11B (Reel 1830)
  - Keokee H.S. (prefabricated school unit), drawing 52-2J (Reel 1830)
  - Thomas Walker H.S., drawing 52-88D (Reel 1831)
  - Loudoun Valley H.S., drawing 53-68B (Reel 1831)
  - Broad Run H.S., drawing 53-74B (Reel 1831)
  - Blacksburg H.S., drawing 60-71C (Reel 1831)
  - Luther H. Foster H.S., drawing 67-30B (Reel 1831)
  - Shop for Williamsburg Negro School, drawing 47-2 (Reel 1831)
  - Patrick County H.S., drawing 70-70A (Reel 1831)
  - Osbourn H.S., drawing 75-68A (Reel 1831)
  - Gar-Field H.S., drawing 75-69A (Reel 1831)
  - Independent Hill, drawing 75-1A, B (Reel 1831)
  - Sudley Elementary, drawing 75-2A (Reel 1831)
  - Sudley Elementary (continued), drawing 75-2A (Reel 1832)
  - Minneville Elementary, drawing 75-3A (Reel 1832)
  - Fred M. Lynn, drawing 75-52B (Reel 1832)
  - Rappahannock H.S., drawing 79-21B (Reel 1832)
  - Graham H.S., drawing 94-92E (Reel 1832)